A Guide to the George W. Palmore Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #38-55
George W. Palmore Papers 1858-1896
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
38-55
ca. 1500 items
Joseph W. Hazelgrove
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the Library on January 9, l933 by Joseph W. Hazelgrove of Farmville, Virginia.
Scope and Content
These papers consist of business and legal papers of George W. Palmore of Cumberland County, Virginia, 1858-1896 and n.d., and contain ca. 1500 items (3 Holl. boxes, 1.5 linear feet). The business papers include accounts, business correspondence, promissory notes, and applications for merchant's licenses.
Many items pertain to his work as postmaster for Stony Point Mills, Cumberland County(ca. 1876-1881); as general state agent for "Cutter" Whiskey, manufactured by C.P. Moorman & Company of Louisville, Kentucky(ca.1888-1893); and as the Richmond agent for Steinhardt Brothers Importers & Company of New York(ca.1894-1896).
Items of interest among the business and legal papers include: the will of George William Palmore(November 7, 1863); a partial copy of the will of John R. Palmore(n.d.); G. W. Palmore's postmaster commission (May 26, 1876); a discussion of the differences in the manufacture of whiskey in the state of Kentucky(July 12, 1888); and a map of the townsite property of the Farmville Coal and Iron Company(1891).
Other items in the collection include: three bound volumes (1890-1895), the journal and bank books of George W. Palmore; a memoriam for Dr. Charles R. Palmore(1882) and a Judge Dabney of Powhatan County (n.d.); and registration lists for "colored" and white voters of Madison township (May 3-10, 1870).
Container List
- Business and Legal Papers, 1858-1874 (Box Box 1)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1875-1876 (Box Box 1)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1877-1880 (Box Box 1)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1881-1884 (Box Box 1)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1885-1888 (Box Box 1)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1889 (Box Box 1)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1890 Jan-Jun (Box Box 1)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1890 Jul-Dec (Box Box 1)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1891 Jan-Jun (Box Box 2)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1891 Jul-Sep (Box Box 2)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1891 Oct-Dec (Box Box 2)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1892 Jan-Mar (Box Box 2)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1892 Apr-Jul (Box Box 2)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1892 Aug-Dec (Box Box 2)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1893 Jan-Jun (Box Box 2)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1893 Jul-Dec (Box Box 3)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1894 Jan-Mar (Box Box 3)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1894 Apr-Jun (Box Box 3)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1894 Jul-Sep (Box Box 3)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1894 Oct-Dec (Box Box 3)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1895-1896 (Box Box 3)
- Business and Legal Papers (Box Box 3)
- 3 Bound Volumes, Journal and Bank Books of George W. Palmore, 1890-1895 (Box Box 3)
- "In Memoriams" for Dr.Charles R. Palmore and Judge Dabney of Powhatan County, 1882 & n.d. (Box Box 3)
- Registration Lists for "Colored" and White Voters of the Madison Township, 1870 (Box Box 3)